<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sectoring Open Source Software</title>
      <link>/findings/sectoring-oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/sectoring-oss/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4, h5 { text-align: center; }  
  Sectoring Open Source Software: Where Do GitHub Contributions Come From? Crystal Zang, Morgan Klutzke, Daniel Bullock, Brandon Kramer, Gizem Korkmaz, and José Bayoán Santiago Calderón Sponsors: Carol Robbins (NCSES) and Ledia Guci (NCSES)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifing Users Across Sectors &amp; OSS in the Business Sector</title>
      <link>/findings/business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/business/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  General Approach To assign users into the business sector, we took an exclusionary approach that depends on the other four sectors. First, we worked to standardize the affiliation column by removing (1) all website domain information using manually curated terms originally based on DataHub&#39;s Domain Entries, (2) all legal entity nomenclature based on manually curated version of Gleif&#39;s legal entity abbreviations, and (3) a list of commonly occurring arbitrary symbols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSS in the Academic Sector</title>
      <link>/findings/academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/academic/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Approach One of the main goals of our summer project is to understand who is producting open-source software (OSS) and important characteristics about them, including which sectors they are embedded within. To classify contributors into the academic sector, we matched GitHub users&#39; email and self-reported affiliation columns to information about universities and colleges from around the world using the Hipo Labs&#39; university domain list - a dataset that has names, countries, and domain names for nearly 9,800 universities across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographical Analyses of GitHub Users</title>
      <link>/findings/geographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/geographic/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Approach To analyze GitHub users by different geographical units, we used regular expressions to recode all self-reported location data available in the GHTorrrent data, finding ~770,000 users with valid country codes. In addition to this self-reported location data, GHTorrent also provides latitude and longitude information for GitHub users (assigned using the Open Street Maps API).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Data &amp;amp; Methods Our work on OSS generally aims to measure how much OSS is in use (stock), how much is created (flow), who is developing these tools, and how OSS tools are being shared within and across different sectors. More specifically, our summer project implements aspects of computational text analysis, probabilistic matching and social network analysis to classify GitHub users into different economic sectors, understand which institutions users are affiliated within each sector, and analyze how users collaborate within and across economic sectors and geographic boundaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Project Overview Current economic indicators and indicators developed by the National Center for Science &amp;amp; Engineering Statistics (NCSES) do not measure the value of goods and services that fall outside of market transactions. Although NCSES does track some types of software development, it is challenging to account for open source software (OSS) outputs because these products are largely being advanced outside of traditional business contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  UVA Data Science for the Public Good The Data Science for the Public Good (DSPG) Young Scholars program is a summer immersive program held at the Biocomplexity Institute’s Social and Decision Analytics division (SDAD). In its seventh year, the program engages students from across the country to work together on projects that address state, federal, and local government challenges around critical social issues relevant in the world today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>